Inventory of the Robert Olney Easton papers, circa 1861-1999
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Robert Olney Easton papers
circa 1861-1999
Easton, Robert Olney, 1915-1999
02833
14.00 cubic ft. (31 Boxes: 28 DOC Boxes, 1 SLD Box, 1 CAR Box, 1 F24 Box and 1 Expandable Envelope)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Papers of this prominent author and environmentalist, including manuscripts, correspondence, photographs, notes, notebooks, clippings, and other miscellaneous memorabilia.
Biography of Robert Olney Easton
Robert Olney Easton, prominent author and environmental activist, was born in San Francisco, California in 1915. He was the son of Robert Easton Sr. and Ethel Olney Easton. He was also the grandson of Warren Olney, one of the founders of the Sierra Club. Easton attended Stanford University in 1933 and 1934 and earned his bachelor’s degree in English from Harvard University in 1938. Between 1938 and 1939, Easton did postgraduate work at Stanford University.
Easton’s literary career began in 1939, when he became associate editor of Coast Magazine. He became a professional free-lance writer in 1941 and published a series of short stories in The Atlantic a year later. Easton’s first book, The Happy Man, was published in 1943. A modern western novel based upon his experiences as a California ranch hand, it was well received by critics and established him as a literary talent. Easton enlisted in the Army during World War II and saw combat in Germany.
Between 1946 and 1950, Easton co-founded and co-edited the Lampasas (Texas) Dispatch. He continued to free-lance throughout the late 1940s and 1950s, contributing short stories to magazines such as Colliers, True, and The Saturday Evening Post. Of particular interest are his stories about Fred Meyer Schroder, an American adventurer who traveled in California, the Yukon, and China, between the 1890s and 1917. Published in True and The Saturday Evening Post, these stories were the foundation of his later works on Schroder.
Easton broadened the scope of his writing during the 1960s. Lord of the Beasts, a biography of American adventurer Charles “Buffalo” Jones co-written with MacKenzie Brown, was published in 1961. In 1963, his article Guns of the American West appeared in The Book of the American West. That same year, he wrote the unpublished article Right Turn in the Rockies, a study of the political far right in the Rocky Mountain region. The Hearing, a novel about the Red Scare of the 1950s, and California Condor: Vanishing American, a book concerning the threatened extinction of the California condor (co-written with Dick Smith), were published in 1964. Easton also edited the anthology Max Brand’s Best Stories (1967) and with MacKenzie Brown, co-edited Bullying the Moqui (1969), which concerned Charles F. Lummis and his exposure of abuses on the Hopi Indian Reservation.
Easton continued to be a productive writer for the duration of his life. Max Brand: The Big Westerner (1970) is a biography of Easton’s father-in-law Frederick Faust, a famed western writer. Black Tide: The Santa Barbara Oil Spill and Its Consequences (1972) was his second work exemplifying his concern with environmental issues. After years of research, Easton wrote two books in succession about Fred Meyer Schroder, Guns, Gold, and Caravans (1978) and China Caravans: An American Adventurer in Old China (1982). Easton turned to historical fiction in the 1980s and 1990s, writing the Saga of California trilogy: This Promised Land (1982), The Power and the Glory (1989), and Blood and Money (1998). He also co-wrote and co-edited three works with his wife Jane Easton: Love and War (1991), Max Brand’s Best Poems (1992), and Collected Stories of Max Brand (1994).
Robert Easton married Jane Faust, the daughter of western writer Frederick Faust (Max Brand) in 1940. They had four daughters: Joan, Katherine, Ellen, and Jane. In addition to his literary activity, Easton was an English instructor at Santa Barbara City College (1959-1965) and a writing and publishing consultant with the U.S. Naval Civil Engineering Laboratory in Port Hueme, California (1961-1969). He was involved in efforts to save the California condor from extinction, helping to found refuges for this bird at Sisquoc Sanctuary (1937) and Los Padres National Forest (1968). He was also active in the civic and environmental affairs of Santa Barbara, California, his adopted hometown.
Robert Olney Easton passed away on November 14, 1999.
Scope and Content
The Robert Easton papers include correspondence, clippings, manuscripts, notebooks, photographs, and other materials concerning his life and literary career. The papers are an excellent primary source about Easton’s literary activities, revealing how he conceived, researched, and developed his works and how they appeared in their final form. They also document the evolution of Easton’s literary style throughout the course of his career.
This collection provides much information about Easton himself. The papers document the events of his life and career and how he coped with them. They also reveal much about the private Robert Easton throughout his adult life. These papers reveal him to be a man heavily influenced by the historical, social, and cultural developments of the American West. They also document the impact these influences had upon his literary work.
Access Restrictions
Correspondence between Robert Easton and Frederick Faust (Max Brand) and between Robert Easton and Jack Schaefer is closed to the public until 2050.
Related Materials
There are other known archival collections created by Robert Olney Easton at:
Easton [Robert O.] Oral History, Collection Number OH9, University of California at Santa Barbara, Donald C. Davidson Library
Robert Olney Easton papers, Texas Tech University, Southwest Collection/Special Collections Library
Papers relating to Robert O. Easton's Lord of Beasts: the Saga of Buffalo Jones, Collection Number AZ 313, University of Arizona Library Special Collections
Acquisition Information
Robert and Jane Easton and the University of California at Santa Barbara donated the Robert Olney Easton papers between 1968-2001.
Access Terms
Brand, Max, 1892-1944.; Faust, Frederick Schiller, 1892-1944.; Morris, Willie.; Schroder, Fred Meyer.; Schaefer, Jack, 1907-; Lummis, Charles Fletcher, 1859-1928.;; Western stories.;;; Photographs.; Authors.
Arts, Humanities, and Social Sciences; Literature; Environment and Conservation
Container List
- Research Files, circa 1861-1996; Series I.
  - Banker Clayton’s Interest, Periodical – Collier’s, December 9, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Black Tide: The Santa Barbara Oil Spill and Its Consequences:
    - Clippings, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bonaparte McPhail:
    - Clippings, August 26, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Periodical – Collier’s, August 26, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Book of the American West – “Guns of the American West:”
    - Brochures, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Clippings, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Notes, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Photographs, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Border Town, Periodical – Holiday, December 1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Brand, Max (Frederick Faust):
    - Clippings, 1967-1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Periodical – Reader’s Digest, December 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Brand, Max (Frederick Faust) – Max Brand: The Big Westerner:
    - Clippings, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Manuscript, p. 1-145, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Manuscript, p. 146-567, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folders 1-3)
    - Manuscript, Index, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Manuscript II, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Periodical – Arizona and the West, Summer 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Brand, Max (Frederick Faust) – Max Brand’s Best Stories, Clippings, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - California Condor:
    - Clippings, 1983, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Periodicals – Miscellaneous, 1965-1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - California Condor: Vanishing American:
    - Clippings, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Galley Proof, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Periodical – This Week in Santa Barbara, December 5-11, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Conquistador, Manuscript, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dynamite’s Day Off:
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Periodical – Atlantic Monthly, May 1942 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - An Eagle in the Sky: Houston, Periodical – Lincoln-Mercury Times, January-February 1950 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Eaton, Arthur:
    - Manuscripts, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Notes, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Farmer Stiles, Clippings, December 1948 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Faro:
    - Galley Proof for Collier’s, November 6, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      (Reproduction)
    - Periodical – Collier’s, November 6, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - The G.I. Farmhands of World War II, Clippings, Spring 1991 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - The Happiest Man: A Story:
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Periodical – Atlantic Monthly, November 1942 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - The Happy Man:
    - Brochures, circa 1993 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Clippings, 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Periodical – Santa Barbara, August/September 1982 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Harvard Lampoon, Clippings, 1936-1938 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - The Hearing:
    - Clippings, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Galley Proof, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Hopkins, Frank T.:
    (Originals in safe)
    - Clippings, 1935-1941 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1971 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and Notes, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folders 6-9)
    - Periodical – The Brand Book, May 1, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Photographs, 1937-1967 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Program - Buffalo Bill Bids You Good-Bye, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook, 1930s (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Italian Heartland, Periodical – Lincoln-Mercury Times, March-April 1952 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Italy:
    - Clippings, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Notebook, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Jones, Charles “Buffalo,” Clippings, June 1984 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Jones, Charles “Buffalo” – The Bull Artist Who Saved the Buffalo:
    - Clippings, September 1964 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Periodical – True, September 1964 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Jones, Charles “Buffalo” – He Lassoed Africa:
    - Clippings, May 1963 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Periodical – True, May 1963 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Jones, Charles “Buffalo” – Lord of the Beasts:
    - Clippings, 1961-1979 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Periodical – Arizona Highways, October 1961 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Lampasas, Texas:
    - Clippings, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Periodical – Lincoln-Mercury Times, September-October 1952 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Legend of Shorm, Periodical – Esquire, September 1956 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Love and War: Pearl Harbor Through V-J Day:
    - Brochures, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Clippings, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Lummis, Charles F.:
    - Clippings, 1946-1964 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1959, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Pamphlets, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Periodicals:
      - 1899-1930 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - 1959-1964 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - 1965-1970 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, 1897, 1911 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      (Reproductions)
    - Publications:
      - 1909-1929 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - 1940-1971 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Lummis, Charles F – Bullying the Moqui:
    - Clippings, 1902-1968 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folders 6-8)
    - Manuscripts – Articles in Out West, 1903, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Manuscripts – Original, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Manuscripts – Revisions, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Notes, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Pamphlets, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Photographs, circa 1903, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Press Release, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Report of the Investigation of Charges Preferred by the Sequoya League of California Against the Management of the Moqui Indian Reservation, 1903, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Lummis, Charles F. – A Study of the Life and Works of Charles Fletcher Lummis, Manuscript, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - The Man Who Went Back:
    - Clippings, May 8, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Manuscript, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Periodical – Collier’s, May 8, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Olney, Warren, Clippings, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Quick and the Cat:
    - Clippings, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Manuscript, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Periodical – Magpie, May 1953 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Right Turn in the Rockies:
    - Brochures, 1957-1963 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Clippings, 1960-1963 (Box 7, Folders 17-18)
    - Clippings, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1960s (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folders 3-5)
    - Manuscripts, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Newsletters, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Notebooks, circa 1963 (Box 8, Folders 8-9)
    - Notes, circa 1963 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Periodicals, 1962-1965 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Press Releases, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Publications, 1945-1962 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Right Turn in the Rockies – Christian Crusade:
    - Brochures, 1960s (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Periodical – Christian Crusade, 1962-1964 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Periodical – The Weekly Crusader, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Publications, 1960s (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Right Turn in the Rockies - Colorado:
    - Clippings, 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Manuscripts, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Notes, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Periodical – The Colorado Alumnus, June 1963 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Right Turn in the Rockies – Education Information Incorporated:
    - Pamphlets, 1959-1964 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Publications, 1956-1963 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Right Turn in the Rockies – Freedom School:
    - Brochures, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Publications, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Right Turn in the Rockies – John Birch Society:
    - Brochures, 1959-1963 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Clippings, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Press Releases, 1960, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Publications, 1955-1963 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Right Turn in the Rockies – Philip M. Stern Family Fund:
    - Brochure, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Proposals, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Right Turn in the Rockies – Utah:
    - Brochures, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Clippings, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Manuscript, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Notes, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Right Turn in the Rockies – Wyoming:
    - Clippings, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Manuscripts, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Notes, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Press Releases, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Publication – American Studies, The University of Wyoming, circa 1963 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - The River, Clippings, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - The Saga of California: This Promised Land:
    - Clippings, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Manuscript – Parts I-III, circa 1982 (Box 10, Folders 6-8)
  - Schaefer, Jack, Clippings, 1977, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer:
    - Clippings, 1907-1956 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1909-1941, 1952-1957, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folders 11-13)
    - Death Certificates, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Membership Certificate – Old Friends, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Notebooks – Large 1-2, November 1953-May 1954 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Notebooks – Large 3-13, 1954-1956 (Box 11, Folders 1-6)
    - Notebooks – Small 1-2, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Notebooks – Small 3-12, 1952-1954 (Box 12, Folders 1-5)
    - Notes, 1955, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Photo Album, circa 1861-1953 (Box 12, Folders 7-8)
    - Photographs, circa 1861-1956 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook:
      - Clippings, 1929-1956 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, 1930-1953 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Manuscripts, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous, 1940s (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Nametags, 1940s (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Programs, 1930-1948 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Publications, 1941-1944 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Ribbons, 1939, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – Adventure on Three Continents, Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer - Alaska:
    - Clippings, 1967-1971 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1978 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Manuscripts, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Notes – Folder 1, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Notes – Folder 2, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, 1890s (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – Alaska-Yukon:
    - Clippings, 1930-1967 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1894 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1975 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Membership Cards, 1904, 1906 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Newsletter – Alaska Yukon Sourdough News, 1942-1975 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Photographs, 1895, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Programs, 1939-1940 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Ribbon, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – Arizona, Correspondence, 1971, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – The Avenging Devil, Periodical – Saturday Evening Post, July 14, 1951 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer - California:
    - Clippings, 1919-1971 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1981 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Manuscripts, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Notes, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Notes – Folder 1, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Notes – Folder 2, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, 1873-1895 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – The Cave Tigers of Hong Kong:
    - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Periodical – True, January 1953 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Publication – True Hunting Yearbook, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer - Chile:
    - Clippings, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1952, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Manuscripts, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Notes, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – China:
    - Calling Cards, circa 1909-1917 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Check – Hong Kong & Shanghai Banking Corporation, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Chinese Characters, circa 1909-1917 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Clippings, 1917-1982 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1912-1918 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1962 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1978 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence – Anderson, William Ashley, 1913-1982 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Membership Certificate – Shanghai Miniature Rifle Club, 1910 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Newsletter – Himalayagram, September 1960 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Notebook, 1909, 1913 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Notes, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Passport, 1915-1916 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Photographs, 1909-1917 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Photostats, 1915, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Post Cards, circa 1909-1917 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Publication – Redwoods of the Past, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – China and Mongolia:
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Notes, 1947-1962 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Photographs, circa 1909-1917 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – China Caravans:
    - Clippings, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Galley Proof, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Manuscript, 1981 (Box 17, Folders 2-3)
    - Photo Album, circa 1909-1917 (Box 17, Folders 4-5)
    - Photographs, circa 1909-1917 (Box 17, Folders 6-7)
    - Press Release, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Publication – Capra Press, Spring 1982 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – China, Mongolia, and Philippines, Photo Album, 1909-1917 (Box 18, Folders 2-3)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – The Cruise of the “Ralph J. Long,” Correspondence, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – Death of the Bullet Proof Bandit, Periodical – True, July 1957 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – The Death of Malunga:
    - Clipping, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Periodicals – True, July 1953 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – Escape With a Mint, Periodical – True, March 1956 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – Guns for Chile:
    - Clippings, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Manuscript, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – Guns, Gold, and Caravans:
    - Clippings, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Manuscript - Parts I-II, circa 1978 (Box 18, Folders 12-13)
    - Manuscript – Part III, circa 1978 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Manuscript – Afterwards, circa 1978 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript – End Notes, circa 1978 (Box 19, Folders 3-5)
    - Manuscripts – Chapters 9-11, 1950s-1970s (Box 19, Folders 6-8)
    - Manuscripts – Chapter 13, 1950s-1970s (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Notes, Chapters 9-14, 1950s-1970s (Box 20, Folders 2-7)
    - Publication – Capra Press, Fall 1980 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – The Last Sea Otter Hunt, Periodical – True, July 1956 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – Mongolia:
    - Clippings, 1963, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1963-1975 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Periodicals – Westways, September 1964 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Photographs, circa 1909-1917 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – The Most Dangerous Game:
    - Manuscripts, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Notes, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – Never Say Die and Opium Tiger, Correspondence, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – Philippines:
    - Correspondence, 1910-1975 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Legal Documents, 1909-1910 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Photograph, 1909 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Photostats, 1910 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – Philippines and Borneo, Notes, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – The Pyramids of Shensi:
    - Clippings, March 1955 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Periodical – True, March 1955 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – “Schroder Story:”
    - Clippings, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1985, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Legal Document, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Manuscripts, 1985, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Notes, 1985, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer - Siberia:
    - Clipping, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1975 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Notes, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Photographs, 1899-circa 1900 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – Siberian Tiger, Correspondence, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – Strike at Seventymile:
    - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Periodical – True, July 1955 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – U.S.S. Revenge, Correspondence, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer – Wild Camel Hunt in Tibet, Periodical – True, December 1955 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Schroder, Fred Meyer - Yukon:
    - Clippings, 1961, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1955-1975 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Manuscripts, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Notes, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Sea Lion Champ, Periodical – Nation’s Business, April 1952 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Thou Shalt Not Abuse the Earth:
    - Clippings, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Periodical – New York Times Magazine, October 12, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 9)